Guide to the Consumer Reports. Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative records, 1904-1988 and undated RL.11793
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative records
1904-1988 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11793
19.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative was a dairy cooperative serving the New York City area, established in 1937 and operated until 1971. The Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative records include clippings, correspondence, facility documents, financial and tax reports, meeting minutes, newsletters, pamphlets and flyers, photographs, sales and distribution records and other printed materials that document the operation of the cooperative and its relations with government agencies, labor unions, supplier dairies and creameries and other associated organizations. Topics discussed in the records include community health, consumer education and protection, government regulation, housing settlements, milk grading and pricing, and milk depots for supply and distribution. Organizations represented include Associated Dairies (now ASDA), Belle Mead Creamery, Cooperative League (now the Twentieth Century Fund), Dairy Farmers Union, Farmers' Educational and Cooperative Union (later the National Farmers Union), Milk Consumers Protective Committee, Rutland Railroad, Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative, the Teamsters Union, and the United States Department of Agriculture. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Administrative Files; General Files; Meyer Parodneck Papers; Milk Cooperative Files; Organizations; Printed Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative was a dairy cooperative serving the New York City area established in 1937 and operated until 1971.
In 1936 residents and members of consumer and civic groups formed the Milk Consumers Protective Committee to represent the interests of milk consumers. Members of this group met with members of the New York Dairy Farmers Union in November 1937 and established the Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative the following month.
Milk delivered by the farmer members was processed by the Cooperative in its own plant and was distributed through cooperative-run milk stations. Stations were set up in settlement houses, housing project recreation rooms and church basements. Milk from these stations sold consistently 2-3 cents below milk prices sold by larger milk companies. Selling milk at the lower price was based on cooperative principle of selling at the lowest prevailing retail rate and then dividing the profits amomg Cooperative members.
In June 1971 the Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative terminated its activities as processor, marketer and distributor of milk and milk products. The Cooperative ended its 33 years of service due to a change in social and economic conditions.
The Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative was led by Meyer Parodneck. Parodneck was born in Poland in 1905 and emigrated to the United States. He graduated from New York Law School in 1925 and ran a number of small businesses. Parodneck developed an interest in the cooperative movement in Europe and in consumer issues in the United States, especially with regard to milk prices in lower income housing developments. He was instrumental in the founding of the Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative in 1937, and served as its president. The Cooperative sold off its assets in 1968 and donated the proceeds to the Consumer-Farmer Foundation which focused more narrowly on housing issues. The Foundation changed its name to the Parodneck Foundation for Self-Help Housing and Community Development in 1994 upon the death of Parodneck in that year.
Source: Consumers Union Archive collection notes; Parodneck Foundation website.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center records:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Investigations
J. Walter Thompson Company. Information Center vertical files
Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks
Collection Overview
The Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative records include clippings, correspondence, facility documents, financial and tax reports, meeting minutes, newsletters, pamphlets and flyers, photographs, sales and distribution records and other printed materials that document the operation of the cooperative and its relations with government agencies, labor unions, supplier dairies and creameries and other associated organizations. Topics discussed in the records include community health, consumer education and protection, government regulation, housing settlements, milk grading and pricing, and milk depots for supply and distribution. Organizations represented include Associated Dairies (now ASDA), Belle Mead Creamery, Cooperative League (now the Twentieth Century Fund), Dairy Farmers Union, Farmers' Educational and Cooperative Union (later the National Farmers Union), Milk Consumers Protective Committee, Rutland Railroad, Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative, the Teamsters Union, and the United States Department of Agriculture.
Consumer education; Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Cooperative societies -- New York (State); Dairy products -- Marketing; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
- Administrative Files, 1936-1976 and undated; 1
  - Accountants' reports, 1938-1970; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1938-1971; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting--Dinner at Belle Mead, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting--Dinner at Belle Mead, 1950-1966 (Box 2)
  - Annual meeting--Dinner at New Paltz, 1946-1962 (Box 2)
  - Annual meeting--Dinner at Norfolk, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Annual meeting--Dinner at Tuckertown, 1946-1955 (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1938-1949 (Box 2)
  - Bylaws and certification of incorporation, 1938-1948 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1976 and undated; 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Delivery schedule--Hillsdale, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Expenses, 1939-1945 (Box 2)
  - Insurance, 1936-1951 (Box 2)
  - Internal Revenue, 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - Internal Revenue Service--Offer in compromise, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Internal Revenue Service--Tax exemption case, 1946-1950; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Labor--IBT (International Brotherhood of Teamsters) Local 854, 1936-1942 (Box 2)
  - Labor--IBT (International Brotherhood of Teamsters) Local 854, 1943-1967 and undated; 15 folders (Box 3)
  - Legal, 1942-1965 (Box 3)
  - Legal--Agreements, 1938-1943 and undated (Box 3)
  - Legal--Amicus Curiae, 1938 (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    H.V. Noyes v. Trevett Co-Op
  - License--New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1936-1949; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - License--New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1950-1969; 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Member Delegate Council, 1940-1943 (Box 4)
  - Newsletter subscription, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Office of Price Administration, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Operations report, 1964-1970 (Box 4)
  - Plant expenses, undated (Box 4)
  - Plant parties, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Press releases, 1936-1957 (Box 4)
  - Printed material (leaflets, broadsides, etc.), 1938-1943 (Box 4)
    In English and Spanish
  - Resolutions, 1938-1961 (Box 4)
  - Sales--General and colleges, 1939-1969 (Box 4)
  - Sales--New York City institutions, 1940-1963 (Box 4)
  - Sales--Retail merchants, 1937-1944 (Box 4)
  - Sponsors, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Statements and radio shows, 1937-1956 (Box 4)
  - Subsidy, 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Treasurer's report, undated (Box 4)
- General Files, 1932-1977 and undated; 2
  - Dies Committee, 1939-1946 (Box 5)
    Martin Dies, Democratic Representative from Texas, chaired a committee on Communist influence in the United States; precursor to the House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC)
  - History--Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1948 (Box 5)
  - History--Martin Young manuscript, undated; 10 folders (Box 5)
    Unpublished project; subjects include history of milk stations; housing and mortgage communities; Meyer Parodneck and other individuals and organizations involved in the cooperative movement
  - Men of the Soil (song) by Harold Hildreth, 1932 (Box 5)
    Song used during the Chicago Milk Strike
  - Miscellaneous notes, articles, printed materials, 1936-1953 (Box 5)
  - New York State--Committee on Consumer Protection, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Newsletters, 1939-1977 (Box 5)
    Other newsletters in Printed Materials
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934-1959 (Box 5)
  - Packaging examples, 1930s (Box 19)
  - Plays--Scripts and playbills, undated (Box 5)
  - Printed materials, 1938-1955 (Box 5)
    Includes form letters, press releases, talking points, etc.
  - Reprints of articles, 1938-1955 (Box 5)
  - Speakers' outline, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - Walker Memorial Fund--Highlander Folk School, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
    Highlander Folk School (New Market, Tenn.) now known as Highland Research and Education Center, is a center for social justice leadership training; fund in memory of Rosanne Walker, a former employee of Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative who died in childbirth.
- Meyer Parodneck Papers, 1933-1988; 3
  - Articles, 1934-1947 (Box 5)
  - Articles--Northeast Union Farmer/Farmer Defender, 1944-1957; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Clippings, 1947-1988 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1957; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1965 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence--Articles, 1934-1937 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence--Individuals, 1938-1967 (Box 6)
    Correspondents include Hartley Cross (Professor of Economics at Springfield and Connecticut colleges; Vice President of Consumers Union; served on the Council of Economic Advisors); Ruth Santoyan (Lieutenant in the Women's Army Corps during World War II); Archie Wright (founder of the Dairy Farmers Union, leader of the Great Milk Strike of 1937); James Peter Warbasse (leader in cooperative education; founder and director of Rochdale Institute; first president of the Cooperative League)
  - Correspondence--Personal, 1937-1959 (Box 6)
  - Speech announcements, notes, etc., 1933-1948 (Box 6)
  - Speech announcements, posters, undated (Box 18)
  - Speeches, statements, etc., 1937-1966 (Box 6)
- Milk Cooperative Files, 1931-1977 and undated; 4
  - Creameries and Dairies, 1938-1977; 1
    - Associated Dairies--Accountants' reports, 1956-1971; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--Agreements with CFMC, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--Appraisal, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--Federal corporation income tax, 1955-1971 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--General, 1959-1965 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--Incorporation, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--New Jersey--Annual reports, 1954-1977 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--New Jersey--Corporation business tax, 1955-1970 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--New Jersey--Department of Agriculture, 1961-1973 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--New Jersey--Personal property, 1963-1971 (Box 6)
    - Associated Dairies--Photograph, aerial view of plant, 1960s (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Belle Mead, 1940-1945 (Box 6)
    - Belle Mead--Appraisal, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Belle Mead--Federal corporation income tax, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Belle Mead--Inventory/Road and extension, 1946-1948 (Box 6)
    - Belle Mead--Liquidation, 1971-1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Belle Mead--New Jersey corporation business tax, 1971-1977 (Box 7)
    - Belle Mead--Photographs, 1940s; 3 folders (Box 18)
      Includes photographs of the exterior grounds, machinery and cheese processing
    - Belle Mead--Title, 1954-1971 (Box 7)
    - Belle Mead/Associated Dairies--Mortgages, 1950-1955 (Box 7)
    - Foremost Milk, 1938-1972 (Box 7)
    - Foremost Milk--Journal, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Legislation, Regulation, etc., 1931-1971 and undated; 2
    - Articles, reports, speeches, etc., 1934-1971; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Articles, reports, speeches--Lyndom O. Simmons: John L. Lewis and the Dairy Farmer, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Federal-State Milk Marketing Order (Order 27), 1939-1953; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Federal-State Milk Marketing Order (Order 27)--Co-op payments, 1953-1967 (Box 7)
    - New Jersey, 1940-1956; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - New Jersey--Report to Secretary of Agriculture, 1963 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Dating, 1953-1961 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Health Department 75% Rule, 1943-1944 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Mayor's Committee on Milk, 1939-1942 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Milk Commission: Is Loose Milk a Health Hazard?, 1931 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Reconstituted Milk Commission hearing, 1931 (Box 7)
    - New York City--Strike by Dairy Farmers Union, 1939 (Box 7)
    - New York City/State, 1934-1966 and undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - New York metropolitan market--Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1938 (Box 8)
    - New York metropolitan market--Hearings, 1938; 7 folders (Box 8)
    - New York State--Analysis of Price Spread in New York City, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
    - New York State--Audit of Milk Dealers and Cooperative Associations, 1938 (Box 8)
    - New York State--Erwin Commission, undated (Box 8)
    - New York State--Milk industry report, 1938 (Box 8)
    - New York State--Regulation of trade practices, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Northeastern Dairy Conference, 1941 (Box 8)
    - Press releases, 1936-1937 (Box 8)
    - St. Louis--Citizens' Milk Investigating Committee, 1948 (Box 8)
    - Warning sign--We Serve Only Raw Milk and Cream, 1930s (Box 8)
  - Milk Stations, 1930s-1969; 3
    - Correspondence, 1942-1965 (Box 8)
    - General, 1948-1965 (Box 8)
    - List of milk stations in New York Boroughs, 1943 (Box 8)
    - Petition--Save the Low Cost Milk Stations, 1930s (Box 8)
    - Sales and Promotion--"A", 1949-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--B-Bronxdale, 1950-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Brownsville-East Bronx, 1949-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Edenwald-Farragut, 1951-1969 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Ft. Greene-Grand Street Settlement, 1948-1967 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Gravesend-Jefferson, 1948-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Johnson-Madison, 1950-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Marcy-"Q", 1949-1967 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Red Hook-Sheepshead Bay, 1942-1966 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--Smith-"V", 1950-1965 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Promotion--"W", 1948-1965 (Box 9)
    - Staten Island, 1960-1969 (Box 9)
  - Printed Material, 1933-1976 and undated; 4
    - Anti-Defamation League--American Jews as Farmers, 1945 (Box 9)
    - Channing L. Bete Company--Milk and You, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Communist Party pamphlets, 1936-1938 (Box 9)
      Includes: Milk for Millions; The Milk Steal
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), 1937-1947 (Box 9)
      Includes: The CIO and the Farmers; To the Farmer from the Customers
    - Cornell Agricultural Experiment Station--Research reports, 1940-1967 (Box 9)
    - Dale Kramer--The Truth About the Farm Bureau, 1940s (Box 9)
    - Farmers Union, 1947-1953 (Box 9)
      Includes: Contest Between the People and the Plunderers; For How Long... Does the Farmer Feed Them All; What's Ahead for Family Farmers
    - Fred Linenger--A Glimpse of the Dairy Industry Abroad Today, 1937 (Box 9)
    - John Sundean--Pamphlet on milk pricing, 1937 (Box 9)
    - Jules Backman--Selected Factors Affecting Pricing of Class 1-A Milk in the New York Market, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Louis Hacker--The Farmer Is Doomed, 1933 (Box 9)
    - Marketing Orders (milk monopoly), 1939 (Box 9)
    - Metropolitan Dairy Institute, 1960 and undated (Box 9)
      Includes: Answers to Your Questions About Milk Dating; Profits in the Milk Industry
    - Milk Committee--Charter of Dairymen's Rights, 1937 (Box 9)
    - Milk for Health, Inc., 1949 and undated (Box 9)
    - Milk grading, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
    - Milk Industry Foundation--Milk Facts, 1940-1949 (Box 9)
    - National Association of Margarine Manufacturers--A Tale of Two Policies, 1938 (Box 9)
    - National Grange--Barriers to Increased Consumption of Fluid Milk, 1955 (Box 9)
    - New York City Department of Health, 1941-1960 (Box 9)
      Includes: Is Federal Milk Regulation the Answer?; New York City Milk Supply and Control
    - New York State bulletins, 1935-1953 (Box 9)
      Includes: Albany Milk Conference; Midshipman Jack; Milk Consumption Habits in the Greater New York Market; Milk Publicity Tax Law Bulletin; To Regulate the Handling of Milk to be Sold in the New York Metropolitan Milk-Marketing Area
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Dairy Situation Bulletin, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Farmers, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Farmers and Farm Laborers' Strikes and Riots in the United States 1932-1935: A List of References (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Henry Agard Wallace, 1933-1934 (Box 10)
      Includes: The Dairy Problem; The Milk Question. Henry Wallace (1888-1965) was Secretary of Agriculture under Franklin Roosevelt and Secretary of Commerce under Harry Truman. Co-founded the Progressive Party in 1946 and ran as candidate for President in the 1948 election.
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Milk Consumption, 1936-1957 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Milk Order Markets, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Milk Pricing, 1937-1956 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Municipal Milk Distribution in Tarboro, North Carolina, 1938 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Orville Freeman (Secretary of Agriculture) statement on Milk Sanitation Bill, 1961 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Department of Justice reports, 1938-1940 (Box 10)
      Includes: Investigation of Milk and Dairy Products Industry; Investigation of Milk and Ice Cream Industries; U.S. v. Borden Company
    - Vermont Agricultural Extension Service--Good Tasting Milk, 1955 (Box 10)
    - VPI (Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University) Extension Division News, 1936 (Box 10)
- Organizations, 1904-1977 and undated; 5
  - Consumer Groups and Cooperative Associations, 1920-1977 and undated; 5
    - Alphabetical files--American Institute of Cooperation to Consumers Union, 1936-1970 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--Co-op Food Market to Council for Industrial Progress, 1934-1966 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--Debs Labor School to Independent Milk Dealers of New York, 1935-1962 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--Italian-American Women's Club to National Consumers League, 1933-1964 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--National Cooperative Milk Producers' Federation to Queens Housewives Committee Against the High Cost of Living, 1936-1953 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--Red Hook Cooperative Society to Union Stores, 1939-1958 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical files--Utah Works Progress Administration to Yorkville Consumers Conference, 1939-1940 (Box 10)
    - Consumer-Farmer Foundation, 1970-1977 (Box 10)
    - Consumers' Cooperative Credit Union, 1920-1941 (Box 10)
    - Consumers' Cooperative Services, 1933-1953; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Consumers' Emergency Council, 1936-1937 (Box 10)
    - Consumers National Federation, 1937-1940 (Box 10)
    - Co-op Education Education Guild of New York, 1954-1965 (Box 10)
    - Co-op Milk Agencies, 1939-1941 (Box 10)
    - Cooperative League, 1931-1952; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Cooperative League--Congress, 1946 (Box 11)
    - Cooperative League--Papers, pamphlets, etc., 1917-1963 (Box 11)
    - Cooperative League--Tour films, 1935-1938 (Box 11)
    - Cooperative League--Tour of Europe, 1934-1936; 6 folders (Box 11)
    - Cooperative League--Tour of Europe/America, 1937-1939 (Box 11)
    - Cooperative League--Yearbooks, 1936, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Discontinued agencies, 1941-1945 (Box 11)
    - Eastern Cooperative Wholesale, 1932-1947 (Box 11)
    - Eastern Cooperatives, 1948-1950 (Box 11)
    - Eastern States Cooperative League, 1932-1944 (Box 11)
    - Emergency Conference of Consumers Organizations (ECCO), 1933-1935; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Federal Cooperative Society (FEDECOS_, 1935-1941 (Box 11)
    - General, 1940-1959 (Box 11)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Bulletins, newsletters, etc., 1938-1942 (Box 11)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Caroline Whitney, 1920-1939; 3 folders (Box 12)
      Caroline Whitney (1901-1938) was Chairman of the Milk Consumers Protective Committee and co-founder of the Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative and served in leadership positions in a number of other consumer and cooperative organizations; economist and statistician who graduated from Vassar and Columbia University. She died suddenly of pulmonary embolism at age 37. Includes clippings, a day book, condolences and correspondence relating to a memorial fund in her name.
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Consumer-Producer Organization Committee, 1937 (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Correspondence, 1936-1943; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Drafts, undated (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Farmer-Consumer Conference, 1937 (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Federal Trade Commission, 1936-1938 (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--General, 1936-1941; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Milk Consumers Protective Committee--Testimonies, speeches, radio, etc., 1936-1940 (Box 12)
    - National Association of Cooperatives, 1945-1950 (Box 12)
    - National Recovery Administration--Consumers National Conference, 1933-1937 (Box 12)
    - New York City Consumer Council, 1938-1949 (Box 12)
    - New York Milkshed Committee, 1949-1953 (Box 12)
    - Organized Housewives of Syracuse, 1935-1943 (Box 12)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Correspondence, 1930-1950; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Correspondence--Creditors, 1936-1937 (Box 12)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Correspondence--Stock liquidation, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Financial, 1933-1936 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--General, 1932-1948 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Heiser Street paving, 1931-1934 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--History (handwritten draft), undated (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Laundry, 1932-1936 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Legal, 1932-1942 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Members, 1932-1949 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Minutes, 1933-1948 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Consumers Cooperative--Newsletters, etc., 1933-1943 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Gardens Community Association--General, 1933-1935 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Gardens Community Association--Jefferson Court, 1931-1936 (Box 13)
    - Sunnyside Gardens Community Association--Minutes, reports, etc., 1931-1936 (Box 13)
  - Housing Associations, 1933-1970; 6
    - Consolidated Home Owners Mortgage Committee, 1933-1939 (Box 13)
    - Cooperative Homes Society--Correspondence, 1935-1941; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Cooperative Homes Society--Incorporation, minutes, etc., 1936-1938 (Box 13)
    - Cooperative Homes Society--Questionnaires, reports, 1937 (Box 13)